Professor, why do we let Luther do this?
Look at this place.
He's done nothing but defile our holy ground.
History has taught us to walk among our enemies.
Okay, while they walk all over us?
I understand your anger, Jeremiah.
But we have no access to these caves without his permission.
Professor Willowbrook, thank you for coming on such short notice.
I, um...
I didn't realize you'd be bringing someone with you, though.
This is Jeremiah Olsclaw,
future leader of the Coache people
and one of my brightest graduate students.
Oh, he may be able to help identify the artifact.
Jeremiah, it's an honor to meet you.
Perhaps you could show us what you found.
Yes, of course.
Miriam?
What do you, uh...
What do you make of this, Professor?
Incredible.
Pollock.
Pollock?
What is Pollock?
Ancient traditional cookware.
Cookware?
Beautiful example.
Jeremiah?
What do you think it is?
Uh, I think the professor is right.
But I think we should take it back to the museum to properly study it.
Oh, no.
Can't leave the cave.
Not until I've had it thoroughly analyzed.
Miriam?
What?
If you are the friend of the Coache that you claim to be,
then why won't you let us take it now?
Professor,
would you give me the artifact, please?
Jeremiah,
you're embarrassing me.
Professor,
this is ancient Coache soil.
Everything in here belongs to us.
No!
Give it to me.
Give me the knife, Jeremiah.
No, no, no!
Find him.
And bring me that knife.
Somebody save me.
Let your wounds break right through.
Don't care how you do it.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
I've been waiting for you.
I've made this whole world shine for you.
Just stay, stay.
Come on.
Let's take a Peroxac, shall we?
Now, young man.
Just stay.
I'm just from the
Don't come here.
gef
You need to make excuses, Naman.
Don't worry.
Your secret is safe with me.
I'm not Naman.
It's just a story on a cave wall.
Until last night, I believed that too.
What happened last night?
Your destiny was revealed.
It's called Pollock, the Starblade.
It's been missing for 500 years.
Until Lionel Luther unearthed it.
It's supposed to shine a light on the true Sigeith
so Naman can identify and destroy his greatest enemy.
And Willenberg came to you because he thinks you're Naman.
I mean, Dad, you should have seen the way he looked at me.
It was kind of overwhelming.
Clark, he thinks you're the savior of his people.
That's a lot to shoulder, even for you.
Yeah, but I'm not.
I mean, I can barely take care of myself.
I see now.
You can't allow yourself to get all tied up in prophecies
written on a cave wall.
Except some of the prophecies are starting to come true.
What?
One of Willenberg's students somehow got a hold of the blade
and has given him powers.
What exactly are we talking about here, Clark?
So far, strength, speed, and he's bulletproof.
How is that possible?
The Quatchi were charged with the blade's safekeeping.
If one of them is holding it, they're
given the power to protect it until they can
deliver it to the true Naman.
Clark, I had your abilities only for a short time.
But believe me. having all of them, I'm going to have to do it.
Well, that power was very intoxicating.
You don't think Jemai is going to give it back?
No.
Clark, you're going to find him and stop him before Lionel
Luther gets a hold of it.
Why won't you listen to me?
I told you I don't want to talk about it.
Note to self, forward all telemarketing calls to Pete.
You want to tell me what that was about?
It was nothing.
Did you pull an all-nighter?
Or do you just find changing clothes every day a little too much?
No.
I'm not.
I was a little laundry impaired this morning.
How bohemian of you.
Hey.
Do you want to cover the gymnastics tryouts?
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Can you find someone else?
Pete Ross passing up the opportunity to ogle Smallville
High's women in spandex?
Look, I just can't do it, OK?
I got to get to class.
Well, hang on a second, and I'll walk with you.
Or not.
What?
Dad, I came as soon as I heard.
Lex, I...
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Would you, uh, excuse us, please?
Yeah, I'm fine, son.
I just, uh, bruised a few ribs.
That's all.
There are rumors floating around
that the person who attacked you
was holding an ancient Kowachi artifact
that supposedly gave him superhuman strength and speed.
Oh.
Well, if that were true, wouldn't that be a prize?
Is that why you've come?
I don't live in the past anymore, Dad.
Someone told me it was a weakness.
Given your recent mishaps in the cave,
maybe you should start following your own advice.
Dad.
Why don't you let me use some of my law enforcement relationships
to track this guy down?
Considering what you and I have been going through recently,
this...
filial concern of yours is...
is touching and a little surprising.
Who are you, Lex?
Dad.
No matter what our difference is,
I'm always gonna be concerned about your well-being.
I'm not gonna be concerned about you.
I'm gonna be concerned about you.
You know, Lex, the only thing more bruised in my ribs is my ego.
Any more publicity would only embarrass me.
So, the cave.
What do you say?
Let's let the matter drop.
All right?
All right.
You didn't get in?
No.
No, I got accepted.
They turned down my financial aid,
which means I can't go.
Well, wait a minute.
Before you commit yourself to pouring lattes in the sunflower state,
why don't you talk to Lex?
Chloe, I'm not asking Lex for a loan.
Why not?
You know he would happily lend it to you.
But I wanted to do this on my own.
Well, selfishly, I would be glad if you decided to stay.
But if Lex were in your shoes,
do you honestly think that he would let one bump in the road
deter him from pursuing his dreams?
Call him.
Here for the prospective students tour club?
Did you do this?
What possible reason would I have
to ransack the office of an obscure teaching assistant?
Then tell me why you're here.
You first.
I'm coming.
Jeremiah,
Jeremiah was gonna help me with a term paper.
Term paper.
So your visit doesn't have anything to do with the fact that he went ballistic in the caves last night
and absconded with a sacred Quachi artifact?
I didn't know.
Well, I'm surprised.
I mean, you usually keep such a close eye on everything that happens in the caves.
But those term papers, you're always writing.
You still haven't told me why you're here.
Well, according to the legend of Neman and Sagith,
this missing artifact bestows extraordinary abilities on whoever possesses it.
You don't really believe that.
I like to keep my mind open to extreme possibilities.
You're starting to sound like your father.
I guess I should be offended, but, uh...
It looks like he's beaten us both to the punch.
Tell me something, Clark.
Do you have any idea what this might be?
Oh.
If you find your friend, tell him I'd like to meet him.
And good luck with your term paper.
Even if I knew where he was, what makes you think he'd listen to me?
But as I understand it, you're not only his academic advisor,
but you're his, uh...
spiritual counselor as well, yes?
So why not just explain to him that the Starblade isn't his to keep?
What do you know about it?
I've read your writings, Professor.
Well, it doesn't belong to you either.
You know I have a considerable amount of influence around here.
Yes?
It's not a threat.
No. Of course not.
But I'm fascinated by your work.
I'm thinking about giving your department a sizable grant
so you can continue your research.
Don't tell me an educated man like you puts stock in old Indian legends.
Look, Professor.
You and I both saw what Jeremiah did in the cave.
I've suspected for some time that there are special human beings
who are capable of feats like that.
Now I know I'm right.
If you've read my work,
then you also know that the blade will crumble if the wrong person touches it.
Yes.
Sageeth.
Who is he?
According to legend, he's the Bearer of Darkness.
Clark.
Well, this is a coincidence.
It's nice to see you.
Professor.
What did he want?
Same thing you do, Naman.
Professor, please stop talking.
Stop calling me that.
One who denies his destiny can bring about as much pain and suffering as your greatest enemy.
Please, Professor. I'm just here to help.
I don't want Jeremiah to hurt anyone, including himself.
This mural was painted on the blinds in his office.
I tried drawing it.
Clark. That's a slumbery place.
A burial ground where the ancient Kwajtch used to perform death rituals.
Jeremiah is writing his dissertation about it.
Does it still exist?
Yes.
Now imperfection.
Jeremiah!
Jeremiah doesn't exist anymore, Professor.
You can't allow the power of the blade to cloud your judgment.
It's made things very clear.
Your duty is to protect the blade for Neman.
He's Neman.
Him?
He's not even Kowachi.
Look, it doesn't really matter who I am.
The blade is dangerous, Jeremiah.
It's given me the strength of ten men.
I could shoot fire from my eyes.
Don't you see, Professor?
I am Neman.
You're misinterpreting the prophecy, Jeremiah.
All these years I've listened to you.
But now I can see you've held me back.
You're afraid that I've become more powerful than you.
Jeremiah, it's the blade.
It's corrupting you.
Just put it down.
I don't take orders from anyone.
I will be the savior of my people.
I will bring Sagith here and kill him!
You don't even know who Sagith is.
You could kill an innocent person.
The man I want is far from innocent.
Stay out of my way, false prophet.
Clark, do you have any idea where he went?
I'm pretty sure he's going after Lionel Luthor.
Because he thinks Lionel is Sagith.
I remember when you first learned about all this from Kyla.
She said that Sagith was supposed to start out as one of the good guys.
The prophecy isn't written down.
It's part of an oral tradition, so it's open to a million different interpretations.
What's your interpretation?
I don't know.
Professor Willowbrook thinks that I'm Neman.
Jarrell wants me to be some sort of Kryptonian warrior, but I just want to beat Clark Kent.
Well, you are Clark Kent, and like it or not, you're the only one who can stop this kid.
We need to warn Lionel.
No.
Jonathan, you just said...
I don't want to give Lionel any information that can help him find this weapon before Clark does.
Son, what you need to do is you need to find Jeremiah before he kills Lionel.
Dad, even if I do find Jeremiah...
I don't know how to get the knife away from him.
Well, if he does have all of your abilities, there's a good chance that he has your weakness, too.
Now, I know what you're going to say.
This faux Egyptian decor is terribly tacky.
So I'm going to need you to just use your imagination, and you will see the potential, okay?
And keep in mind, location, location, location.
Hi.
Can I help you?
Yes.
Earl Grey, please, and whatever my client wants.
Yeah, take a look.
Up on the second floor, there's a very nice living space, office.
Ma'am, I think there's been a misunderstanding.
Talon's not for sale.
Well, it is, dear.
Lex Luthor hired me to sell it.
Excuse me.
I'm part owner.
You can't just...
I'll take it up with you.
You can't just sell the Talon without consulting me.
I thought that's what you wanted, so you could afford to go to Paris.
No, I asked you to buy me out of my share.
I didn't ask you to sell the building.
Either way, you get the money.
I put my heart and soul into that place, Lex.
My friends hang out there.
It's a sanctuary for them.
I do not want it turned into a Kinko's.
Lana, this may come as a shock to you, but the Talon's not exactly a cash cow.
And personally, I have no interest in the coffee business.
It's much more profitable to sell the building.
If the Talon is such a terrible investment, then why'd you keep it this long?
I thought that was obvious.
I did it for you.
I spent so much time swimming with Wall Street sharks and boardroom barracudas that it's been nice to come up for every so little.
I'm sorry.
You can't be so soft and with someone as honest and pure-hearted as you.
In some ways, you're the best partner I've ever had.
Thank you, Lex.
But you're leaving.
And you're irreplaceable.
So why hang on to something that's over?
Unless, of course, this is really about you having second thoughts.
What?
No, I...
Because you gotta ask yourself, Lana.
Who are you?
Are you a small-town girl content to spend her days
gossiping in a coffee shop with her friends?
Or are you the girl who goes to Paris?
I don't know.
What do you want?
The same thing as you.
To ensure the well-being
of the people of Paris.
To ensure the well-being of the people of Paris.
I'm unable to find it.
You honestly believe that I'd help you?
Why are we playing games?
Clark, you're as eager as I am
to unlock the mysteries of the cave.
Even if I wanted to help you,
the Coati don't take orders from me.
Don't be modest.
I'm sure they believe as I do.
You're a very...
special young man.
They'll believe you.
You can also tell the professor
that I can turn
from being a loyal ally
to his very formidable nemesis
in a heartbeat.
A friend who becomes the enemy.
I beg your pardon?
Mr. Luther, those caves may not belong to my family,
but this barn does.
So get out.
Professor.
Have you found Jeremiah?
Not yet, but I have an idea.
I need your help.
I'm at your service, Naman.
I know you want to believe it,
but I'm not your savior.
Did you ever think that Jeremiah really is Naman?
He has all the abilities foretold in the prophecy,
and he's going to try and kill Sagith.
True.
But he did not fall
from the sky in a rain of fire.
Jeremiah is desperate
to be someone he's not.
And you are desperate
not to be someone you are.
Professor, I may be confused about who I am,
but one thing I'm not is a killer.
You'd be surprised what you're capable of
when the time comes.
Now, how can I help you?
Well, if I can't find Jeremiah,
maybe I can get him to come to me.
Do you have any way to contact him?
I could try to pass him a message
to other members of the tribe,
but after last night,
I doubt if he'll listen to me.
That depends on the message.
What are you doing here?
Professor Willowbrook sent me a message.
He told me that after he saw what I could do,
he knew he was wrong.
I'm the true Neman.
I never claimed to be Neman.
Liar!
Willowbrook says you're a false prophet,
that before I kill Sigeith, I have to kill you.
What's this?
Danny, what's...
What's happening?
Danny, why have we stopped?
Danny?
Hey.
I thought I held a monopoly on burning the candle at both ends.
Actually, I was just heading to the torch to print out my term paper.
Oh, yeah.
Look at our extracurriculars if you can't milk them for office supplies.
Just, um, lock up when you're done,
and try to turn everything off, okay?
Okay.
Oh, hey!
I saw your mom at the courthouse.
You didn't tell me she was up for federal judgeship.
Actually, she doesn't have the job yet.
Oh, but, I mean, with her record, she's a shoo-in.
I was talking to a couple of people...
You don't stop until you get your scoop, do you?
I was just trying to show a little interest in your life.
I'm your friend, Pete.
I'm not just some random reporter.
Oh, you see, that...
That's the problem.
You're both.
And it's pretty obvious which one comes first.
What's with you, Pete?
Not everything is public domain, Chloe.
Now I understand why Clark gets so mad at you
for trying to bust into his private life.
Here.
nose.
Here?
And distance.
And quite frankly, I'll do anything for you.
You had me worked out that you're not a loved enemy polyamory.
In the name of fleet secret.
I am no longer an actress.
And all of that, taken out of the project Pompey's saw
You better hurry, sweetheart.
Come on, Clark.
Jonathan, how did you...
I have no idea.
Mom? Dad?
Sweetheart, thank God.
What happened?
We found you bleeding to death.
Blade must have been made of Kryptonian metal.
I guess my body's not as strong as it used to be.
Your body healed itself.
Actually, your father did it.
How?
I have no idea, Clark.
One minute I was over you trying to stop the blood,
and the next minute you were healed.
You saved my life.
I didn't save your life, son.
I was just the vessel.
Fitzgerald.
However it happened, we should be grateful.
He's not done with either of us, is he?
Clark, Lex called last night.
Jeremiah has Lionel.
I know where they are. I'll go.
Clark.
Jeremiah tried to kill you.
Martha.
Let him go.
Ş.
Bidasur planörung.
Cengiz A erase.
Cavalry of the Elam.
What do you suggest we should do?
Such inhuman brilliance.
Uncomfortable bushfire energy is giving us danger.
Unclear Israelites are like children's enjoyable bonds.
Maybe they're seen as ret源 of fire.
We shall be But we shall bring hope
and joy to the land of Ellota.
The rest are slaves.
And ending us?
I don't know how you survived.
But you won't do it twice.
Dad!
Hey, Lex.
It's Jeremiah.
Where's Jeremiah?
I don't know, Dad.
But I'm gonna get you out of here before he comes back.
All right.
Come on.
I guess having all those abilities really took a toll on his body.
Well, son, at least we know that the knife won't ever hurt you or anybody else again.
It also means the prophecy came true.
The blade glowed and then disintegrated when they touched it.
Which means either Lionel or Lex is my greatest enemy.
Did you see which one grabbed it first?
No.
But I don't need a blade to tell me that Lionel Luther is a bad person.
If you're going to believe this legend,
you have to face the possibility that it could be Lex.
I'm not ready to do that.
Clark, the Kowatchi think that you're a savior.
Jor-El wants you to be a conqueror.
Now, knife or not, you can't let other people tell you what to be.
Who do you think I'll become?
I don't know.
You could be the world's greatest hero.
Or its most mild-mannered citizen.
But the only person who can be that.
Who can write your story.
Is you.
Is this where they're holding the partnership meeting?
We got another offer.
Chloe and her dad.
Ugh.
Never would have predicted that one.
They want to keep the place exactly as it is.
And let me stay on as part owner so, uh,
I can go back to work when I get home from school in Paris.
Sounds too good to pass up.
I turned them down.
Without consulting me?
I don't think Chloe was ever really interested in running the business.
Or running the place anyway.
I think she was just having some trouble letting go of the past.
But, um, I don't want anything pulling me back to Smallville.
I thought about what you said, Lex.
About who I am.
And, um, I decided...
I'm the girl that goes to Paris.
So I'm up for a little while.
Chloe, what are you doing here?
I think I should be asking you that.
You just give me a minute and I'll get out of your way.
You know, when my parents split, I head out in the garage.
I don't have my driver's license yet.
Your mom called today.
She asked me if I'd seen you and I said I hadn't.
She tried to brush it off.
She said you were probably hanging out with Clark.
But you weren't.
Mystery solved.
Yeah.
I'm guessing that you didn't tell me about your mom's job offer because it wasn't a good
thing, is it?
I thought she'd turn it down right away.
It doesn't look like that's gonna happen.
Well, having been through my own version of divorce court, I know how difficult it can
be.
Do you think there's any chance that they'll work it out?
My dad's helping her move to Wichita.
I guess I just didn't realize how bad it was between them.
This just seems like an excuse for her to leave.
Just feels like it's somebody else's life and not mine.
I'm sorry.
Alright, olvidated.
I mean, you wanted me on the wrong side, don't you?
Or are you looking somebody else's way?
For some reason, it's sort of lonely here, to be honest.
Look, I'm not going to do anything to move in with something I regret.
Student clock, discuss this with værn.
Oh...
Uhh...
You know, I've been...
This Neman guy is supposed to come from the stars,
have the power of ten men, and shoot fire from his eyes, right?
It's just an allegory, Lex.
I know.
But if one person could do all that,
he would be a formidable enemy.
He could conquer the world.
He could become a tyrant if nobody kept him in check.
So I've been thinking,
anybody who'd be willing to fight him
would have to be pretty brave.
Clark,
did it ever occur to you that maybe the hero of the story
would be the one who would be the hero of the story?
No.
It's the geath.
Thank you.